<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-07T10:24:04-05:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">nikolay’s random posts</title><subtitle>A mix of data science, software engineering and politics. Powered by Fastpages, Jekyll and Github.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Self-medication: not an alternative to the classical health service provision but an addition to it</title><link href="/2021/07/05/self-medication.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Self-medication: not an alternative to the classical health service provision but an addition to it" /><published>2021-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-07-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/07/05/self-medication</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Self-medication has a negative connotation attached to it. The established norm is that it is wrong. You are supposed to always consult your doctor. I am not sure how often this is said as a sort of legal hedge (‘I don’t want you to sue me’) or simply out of habit.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Защо България хаби милиарди за да придобие 2 кораба?</title><link href="/2021/06/23/bg-navy01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Защо България хаби милиарди за да придобие 2 кораба?" /><published>2021-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/06/23/bg-navy01</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Поводът за тази пост е днешната статия в Капитал.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Numpy Array Ranks and Reshaping</title><link href="/2021/01/26/numpy-array-ranks-reshapes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Numpy Array Ranks and Reshaping" /><published>2021-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-01-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>/2021/01/26/numpy-array-ranks-reshapes</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accepting a Credit Card: a SaaS application in a nutshell (Stripe, Rails4, Devise3)</title><link href="/2015/08/04/accepting-credit-card-stripe-saas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accepting a Credit Card: a SaaS application in a nutshell (Stripe, Rails4, Devise3)" /><published>2015-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-08-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2015/08/04/accepting-credit-card-stripe-saas</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Recently I blogged about a light-touch workflow which allows registration without setting a password. This blog post and the accompanying git repository take it from there and add credit card registration via Stripe. I was thinking of what could the absolutely minimal SaaS application and came with the conclusion that it recording the credit card details constitutes the absolutely irreducable bit - without it you can’t have a SaaS application. So, this lengthy blog post is about creating such a minimal SaaS application that does nothing but allowing people to sign up and record their credit card details.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Overriding Devise to Skip Setting of Password (Rails4, Devise3)</title><link href="/2015/07/24/overriding-devise-to-skip-setting-of-password.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Overriding Devise to Skip Setting of Password (Rails4, Devise3)" /><published>2015-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2015-07-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2015/07/24/overriding-devise-to-skip-setting-of-password</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking about a light-touch workflow which allows a prospective user to register without setting a password. My first idea was to override the confirmable module (i.e. to invite the user to set a password as part of the confirmation) but I dropped it as it introduces an interim state (an unconfirmed account) and for me this is an unnecessary complication. My idea was to make the registration simpler and requiring a confirmation would be the exact opposite.</summary></entry></feed>